Guide to the Jane Kilbourne papers, 1908-1972 and undated RL.11754
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jane Kilbourne papers
1908-1972 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kilbourne, Jane Elizabeth
RL.11754
3.0 Linear Feet
Jane Kilbourne was a journalist, editor and public relations executive primarily with Pan American airlines, based in New York. Collection includes correspondence, clippings, photographs, scrapbooks and published articles that document Kilbourne's career with Pan Am as a public relations executive and publications editor specializing in women's issues and interests regarding travel, food and fashion design. Collection also documents international fashion shows sponsored by Pan Am and attended by Kilbourne. Companies represented in the collection include Estee Lauder and the International Air Transport Association (IATA). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Jane Kilbourne was a journalist, editor and public relations executive primarily with Pan American airlines, based in New York.
Born 1908, New York. Graduated Kimberley School 1927; Douglass College, 1928. Worked at Pan American airline 1943-approximately 1974. Died 1991, Connecticut.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Jane Kilbourne papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2015.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. 16mm microfilm Treasurer's Office records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. John F. Devine papers
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, clippings, photographs, scrapbooks and published articles that document Kilbourne's career with Pan Am as a public relations executive and publications editor specializing in women's issues and interests regarding travel, food and fashion design. Collection also documents international fashion shows sponsored by Pan Am and attended by Kilbourne. Companies represented in the collection include Estee Lauder and the International Air Transport Association (IATA). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Travel; Travel writing; Fashion -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Clothing and dress; Advertising -- Clothing and dress; Fashion design -- History -- 20th century; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Pan American World Airways, Inc.
- General Files, 1908-1972 and undated; 1
  - Baby record, 1908-1909 (Box 1)
  - Beauty Fashion magazine, 1972 (Box 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Beauty makeover article p. 10
  - Biographical sketch, undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1947-1958; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Event itineraries, menus, etc., 1950-1955 and undated (Box 1)
  - International Air Transport Association (ITSA) meeting booklet, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Pan-American World Airways--Annual report, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Pan-American World Airways--Clipper newsletter, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Pan-American World Airways--Clipper Trip; McCall's Flight Light Wardrobe/Macy's catalog, undated (Box 2)
  - Pan-American World Airways--New Horizons magazine, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Pan-American World Airways--Print advertisements, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Pan-American World Airways--Round the World Flight, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Santa Barbara Pictorial, undated (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook--Couture Internationale style show, Manila, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook--Pan Am, 1943-1947 (Box 4)
    Includes clippings, correspondence, articles on food and fashion, photographs of events and store window displays
  - Scrapbook--Pan Am/Estee Lauder beauty makeover project, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook--Women's magazines presentation, 1950; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook pages, 1945-1949 (Box 2)
  - Who's Who of American Women entry, 1969 (Box 1)
  - World Airlanes magazine, 1949 (Box 2)
- Photographs, 1909-1970 and undated; 2
  - David McCabe photograph, undated (Box 1)
  - Fashion-Hawaii show, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Grand Duchess of Luxembourg, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Hawaii, undated (Box 1)
  - International fashion show, undated (Box 1)
  - Jane Kilbourne, Julia Arnold, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Japan, undated (Box 1)
  - Jay Te Winburn photographs, undated (Box 1)
  - Lockheed C-130 Transport, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Middle East, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1962-1964 and undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Pan Am flight attendants, undated (Box 1)
  - Personal, 1909 and undated (Box 1)
  - Scandinavia, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Stan Horstman, undated (Box 2)